["BUMBLE BEE [STING ME]"
[BY WILSON PICKETT PLAYING]
♪ Hey, bumblebee ♪
♪ Come on and sting me... ♪
[HUGH] SoCal Tower, this is 895-Alpha.
I have reached altitude.
895-Alpha, roger that.
We hear this is the maiden
flight of your new twin-engine.
That's right.
Sold my ad agency after 30 years.
This little birdie,
she's my reward, honey.
895-Alpha... honey?
It's just a term
of endearment, SoCal Tower.
Geez, can't be nice to people anymore.
SoCal Tower, is there
a weather system up ahead?
Not that I'm aware of.
Stand by.
[BUZZING]
What the...?
SoCal Tower, it's some kind of insects.
895-Alpha, insects?
Yeah! Ow!
Yeah, it's bees, SoCal Tower!
Bees! In-in-in and around the aircraft.
- Ow! Ow!
- Copy.
Requesting a runway
for emergency landing.
[GROANING]
[ALARM BEEPING]
Traffic alert.
[LIZ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, God, oh, God!
No, no!
Oh, God!
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -
LAFD Engine Company 118.
At best, a work in progress.
Firefighter Wilson.
Your boots are scuffed.
They should be polished
to a high luster.
Unsatisfactory. Do it again.
Yes, sir.
Firefighter Han.
[SPITS]
On a clean floor,
that would spread evenly.
Instead, it's globbing.
Unsatisfactory.
Do it again.
Copy you, Captain Gerrard.
Diaz, did you shop for mess today?
First thing, Cap.
Chief's up my ass
about budget cuts,
and you're buying organic fruit leather.
Unsatisfactory.
I'll do better next time, sir.
Nice mustache, by the way.
Thank you, sir.
Buckley, why are there loops
in the hose bed of that apparatus?
Loops make for a faster carry.
Captain Nash...
Captain Nash quit three months ago.
You see that construction crew?
You know what they're building?
My 118.
Security fencing. Cast-iron plumbing.
And my hose bed folded high and tight.
Scrub the crapper. One week.
Already gave me latrine duty, sir.
Two weeks.
Everyone, shorts and sneakers.
Run pickups around the station
until the tone sounds
or he pukes.
Have fun with it.
Captain Maynard, you wanted to see me?
- Athena, thanks for coming.
- Sergeant Grant.
Assistant United States Attorney
Spencer, district of California.
This is my colleague from Arizona,
AUSA Lawrence.
Athena, these men have
a special assignment for you.
Sergeant, have a seat.
[SIGHS]
How much do you know
about Maxwell Fulton?
The sex trafficker?
As little as possible.
Beverly Hills broker,
went away about a year ago...
for pimping underage girls
to his bigwig buddies.
You may not have heard he hanged himself
in federal prison last week in Phoenix.
[ATHENA] I'll cry later.
What does this have to do with me?
[LAWRENCE] Well, Fulton had a cellmate,
a prisoner we assigned him
in hopes he'd open up.
At trial, Fulton refused to ID
any of his investors who,
uh...
Raped those girls.
We'd like you to escort that prisoner
from Phoenix back here to L.A.
to be deposed before a grand jury.
It's Dennis Jenkins.
We're aware you have
a history with Mr. Jenkins.
He murdered your friend...
My fiancé.
Dennis Jenkins...
murdered my fiancé.
And he got away with it
for more than 30 years until I found him
and brought him to justice.
And now he has made some kind of deal
with the federal government?
He's a cooperating witness.
And what exactly is he getting
in exchange for this cooperation?
Time off?
Early release.
You're setting him free.
You're setting him free?
He murdered a police officer!
Gentlemen, give us a moment.
- Elaine!
- I'm sorry.
I wanted to talk to you first.
They wouldn't let me.
Why are they asking me to do this?
Chaperone Emmett's killer to freedom?
They aren't asking.
Dennis Jenkins is.
He requested you.
[GASPING FOR BREATH]
[PANTING]
[EDDIE] Don't jump.
Why not?
Gerrard would just make us
clean you up off the sidewalk.
Guys, I-I-I can't do this anymore.
Okay, I-I made a decision.
I think we should all quit.
[HEN SCOFFS]
You think we should all quit?
[BUCK] Yeah, if we do it
at the same time,
maybe leadership would
realize they made a mistake
and they'll have to bring Bobby back.
But then we wouldn't be here.
You got to stop letting
this guy get under your skin
- like this, Buck.
- [CHIMNEY] Seriously.
Buck, listen, he keeps coming
after you because you react
and talk back.
O-Of course I talk back.
In fact, why don't you guys?
I'm not a fan of scrubbing the crapper.
[HEN] And I can't afford to.
Okay? I-I need this job.
I have to show stability.
I'm still trying to fight to get
my foster care license reinstated.
And I got two kids at home.
At least until she gets
her foster license reinstated.
Okay, well, what-what-what
if we get him fired?
Oh. We did... years ago.
He came back.
Like Michael Myers
with a push-broom mustache.
No offense, Magnum.
I served under guys
like Gerrard in the Army.
He's all bluster.
Just got to keep your head down,
follow orders.
Eventually, he'll move on
to the next target.
[SIGHS] I-I wish Bobby was here.
[CHIMNEY] If Bobby was here,
we wouldn't be having this conversation.
Has anybody talked to him?
I think he's been pretty busy
with his new crew.
- [SIREN WAILING]
- [COUGHS]
- Help!
- [WOMAN 2] Help! Help me!
[WOMAN 1] Help!
[WOMAN 2] Up here! Help me!
Help me, please!
Scanlan, Dabney, I want a hose
on that third-floor window
five minutes ago!
[OVER RADIO] Sanchez, Jones,
pump and dump from the north.
- Shapiro.
- Yes, sir.
- Get that ladder extended.
- On it, Captain.
I want a round-trip ticket to the roo...
[BRITISH ACCENT] Bloody hell! Come on!
[DIRECTOR] Cut.
It's a dog's breakfast today, mate.
Sorry, Brad, I know.
We just need to block this
a little better, okay? Uh,
where's, uh, what's-his-name,
the tech advisor?
Fly in the technical advisor, please.
Anyone have eyes on our fire chief?
Uh, it's captain, not chief.
It's the chief who sent me here.
Well, Mr. Not-Chief,
maybe you can help us out.
We seem to be having
a little trouble here.
Yeah.
That's because you're directing
these two firefighters
to suppress a fire from downwind,
which you wouldn't do,
and also sending guys
into a crossfire. Oh, by the way,
"pump and dump"...
that's not a thing anyone says.
We'll handle the dialogue.
We just need this untangled.
Copy that. Okay.
So what you don't want
to do is you don't want
to cross
your advancing hose lines. Here.
That way, you can fight the fire
without decapitating
your captain in the process.
Hey, thank you for that.
[DIRECTOR] Okay, okay,
that's great. Thank you very much.
We'll holler if we need you again. Brad.
[FIRST A.D.] Everybody back to one!
Crane's moving!
♪ My honey in the summer... ♪
[REYLA] Kara says
we're shoo-ins for the finals,
but Callie says she's delusional.
Well, it sounds like Callie hasn't seen
your new jump shot we're working on.
No, I think she's just salty
because Kara and David M.
Are hooking up.
Sweetie, what do you mean, "hooking up"?
- [HORNS HONKING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- Mom!
- [GASPS]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[SCREAMING]
- [PANTING]
- [BEES BUZZING]
[GASPS] Reyla, Reyla, baby, are you okay?
[GROANING]
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God. [GASPS]
- [MAN] Let me in the car.
- [REYLA AND JULIE SCREAMING]
- Please, please, please.
[MAN GROANING]
[GASPING]
_
You said bees?
Yes. I-I think the truck was
carrying them. The driver...
I think they killed him.
And now they're all over our car.
[REYLA] Mommy, I'm scared.
How many people are with you?
Me and my daughter Reyla.
She's eight.
And she's allergic to bees.
My name's Maddie. I'm going
to stay on the line with you
until help arrives. Do you carry an Epi?
Yes. [SIGHS]
- Yes, I found it.
- Good.
Hopefully, you won't have to
use it. Just stay where you are.
- [HORN HONKING]
- [SIRENS WAILING]
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
That's a lot of bees.
[BEES BUZZING]
You know, a swarm can generate
as much electricity
as a storm cloud.
Good, 'cause I forgot
to charge my phone.
[JOSH] Okay, people,
we're treating this
like any other toxic spill.
Hopefully, this stays contained
to the Fourth Street Bridge.
We've got a mandatory shelter-in-place
from Alameda to the 101.
Anybody gets a call
from a rooftop, a balcony,
a street, just tell them
to get the hell inside.
Truck's coming out of Temecula.
It left before dawn.
It was supposed to arrive
in Fresno two hours ago.
Wait. So, what happened?
Gridlock on the 101.
Apparently, the truck has to be
in motion to create airflow,
and heat makes the bees angry.
Well, it's 92 degrees today.
How many angry bees
are we talking about?
That truck was hauling
22 million killer bees.
Okay, ladies and idiots, heads
out of your asses and extricate.
Fog streams up ASAP.
And full PPE!
I don't need any of you
getting any uglier today.
[HEN] Copy that, Cap.
Sir, yes, sir.
[CHIMNEY] Coming in. Clear!
[HEN] No pulse.
Dispatch, the driver's a black tag.
Trucking company says there should be
a second driver.
Checking now.
Oh, hey, Maddie, we're at the SUV,
but we have zero visibility.
[MADDIE] Driver is Julie Watson,
32. Her eight-year-old daughter
is in the back seat
with a severe bee allergy.
She hasn't been stung yet, but...
She will be as soon
as we open these doors.
Let's grab the CO2.
I got him!
We got you, sir.
He's breathing, but barely.
- I'm out of CO2!
- Me, too.
Not that it's doing much.
Cap, we need more firepower.
You're out of luck.
Damn bugs jammed the intake.
Pumper can't pump. Dispatch,
I need a foam carrier and four
more engines on the double!
Engines are en route, but the
foam's in traffic in Van Nuys.
20 minutes out.
They put lead in your coffee over there?
Get it now!
Oh, no. [WHIMPERS]
No, n-no, no, no, no, no, no.
One got inside. How did it get inside?
No, don't swat at it, Julie. Stay calm.
Check the air vents on your dashboard.
Oh, God.
Julie, close them now.
[PANTING]
Okay, they're closed.
How many got in?
I don't know, uh,
two or three maybe?
If one of them stings, it'll trigger
an alarm response in all the others.
Okay, Julie, try
and keep your eye on them,
but I need you to both
stay very, very still.
Like a statue, okay, Reyla?
[SIGHS] Like a statue. Like a statue.
- [BEEPING]
- He's got minimal stings, considering,
but I'm not getting a chest rise.
O2 sat's at 40. All right,
checking his airway for obstruction.
[BUZZING]
Found the obstruction.
[MADDIE] Sit tight, you
two. You're doing great.
[REYLA WHIMPERS]
Go away, stupid bee!
- Reyla, no!
- [GASPS]
[MADDIE] Julie, what happened?
I... It stung her.
Okay, we're-we're not gonna panic.
Julie, you said you had the Epi?
Yes, uh, I've got it.
- Have you ever used one before?
- Yes.
On your daughter?
On myself.
Wait. You're allergic, too?
Bee allergies run in our family.
Okay, careful, Julie.
The pheromones. Any other bees
in the car are going to be
extra aggressive right now.
Mom... [PANTING RAPIDLY]
- I can't breathe.
- I know.
Julie, give Reyla the shot in her thigh.
Quick ouchie. Okay? Blue to the sky,
- orange to the thigh, and...
- [GASPS]
Did you do it, Julie?
Yeah.
How's your breathing, Reyla?
[SIGHS]
It feels better. [PANTING]
- [BUZZING]
- [GASPS]
Mom, did it sting you?
[SOFT GASPING]
Maddie,
how soon can we get help?
[MADDIE] 118, patient in the sedan
is experiencing an allergic reaction.
We need to pull her out now.
Hear that, boys? Chop-chop!
Cap, there's an eight-year-old
girl in the car.
Allergies aside,
a kid that weight can only
take 40 to 50 stings.
We pull her out in this swarm,
I don't like her odds.
[EXPLOSION]
Damn it! Get CO2 on that
till we get the water flowing!
Move! Move!
- [BEEPING STEADILY]
- Suction's up.
[BEEPING RAPIDLY]
[HEN] Blood pressure's dropping.
Sir? Willy, we're almost there.
- All right, that should do it.
- Sternal rub.
Willy, come on.
- Come on, come on.
[GASPS]
There we go. All right.
O2 sat's back to 90.
I'm starting a line.
Why do I taste honey?
[CHUCKLES]
Dispatch, where's my damn foam?!
Eight minutes out, but
I'm sending a police escort.
Might have it in six.
No. The people in that car
won't live till then.
Get it now!
Eddie, smoke. Smoke calms bees.
- What?
- Yeah, it's what beekeepers use
to stop 'em from stinging.
We get the PPV fans off the rig.
We use it to blow smoke over the car.
[MADDIE] Julie, can you hear me?
[LABORED BREATHING]
They're not gonna make it
to me, are they?
I have a plan.
We're gonna use that injector again.
I already... used it up.
Yes and no. If you crack it open,
we can get an extra dose out of it.
Do you have anything sharp on you?
I have a pair of scissors
in my school bag.
Good girl, Reyla. Can you get them?
- Got 'em.
- Hand them to your mom.
Now, Julie, carefully cut
the plastic casing.
[WHEEZING]
Okay.
Now what?
You'll see a little syringe inside.
Take it out, pull up
the plunger, just a little bit.
[JULIE WHEEZING]
I'm doing... [INHALES SHARPLY]
[BREATHING QUIETS]
Mom?
Mom.
Mom, please wake up.
She's not breathing.
Okay, Reyla, your mom needs your help.
Can you do exactly as I say?
I'll try.
Fans are up!
Buckley!
What the hell are you doing?
[MADDIE] Reyla, you can do this.
Okay, little guys.
Stay cool.
Deep breath.
[INHALES SHARPLY]
It's in.
Now what?
Press the plunger halfway down.
Did it.
Mom.
Give it a second.
Nothing's happening.
Mom? Mom. Mom, please wake up.
Mom.
[INHALES SHARPLY, BREATHES AIRILY]
- [PANTING]
- She's breathing.
Maddie, it worked.
[SIGHS SOFTLY]
[JULIE SIGHS]
LAFD, ma'am. We got you.
[JULIE EXHALES]
- Nice and easy.
- [EDDIE] Here you go.
- You got her?
- [BUCK] I got you.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[GERRARD] Foam's landing any second.
Let's mop this sucker up.
Buckley, that smoke thing.
That was some independent thinking.
Uh, thank you, sir.
KP duty. One month.
[EDDIE LAUGHS]
KP duty?
[LAUGHTER]
Is that a...?
It's a bee-nado.
[BUZZING]
[SIREN WAILING]
I like this house,
just not the neighborhood.
And I like this neighborhood...
Huh? Ugh.
But that house is terrible.
Well, we're not in any hurry.
Insurance will pay for this
place till the end of the year.
- Is that all you're taking?
- Just going to Arizona.
I'll be back before dinner tomorrow.
Why'd you say yes?
Since when do you do prisoner transfers?
[SCOFFS]
Since this prisoner refuses to testify
unless I'm the one who travels him.
Yeah, maybe he knows he can trust you.
Or maybe he wants to gloat,
rub my face in the fact that
he's getting an early release.
You don't really think that.
You said the day you found Jenkins,
he seemed genuinely remorseful.
[SIGHS]
You know, I used to think
that putting Emmett's killer
behind bars would free me.
But the moment
I heard Dennis Jenkins' name,
I was right back there...
[SCOFFS] seeing him living the life
that Emmett never had the chance to.
And now he gets to go back to it.
[CLOSES ZIPPER]
Hey.
[SIGHS]
Why don't you let me come with you?
[LAUGHING] What?
- And have you give up show business?
- [LAUGHS SOFTLY]
Epinephrine and calamine lotion
have been flying off store
shelves all across the Southland
after a long-haul truck
carrying some 22 million killer bees
jackknifed today just east of Downtown.
And we're hearing that
the hives now have merged
into what entomologists are calling
a "super swarm," 15 million strong.
Our own Jackie Blanchard
has been following
this noisy cloud. Jackie?
Dwight, I'm here in Valley Village
where the super swarm was last seen.
Experts have been tracking
the cloud on Doppler radar,
but it fell off just before sunset.
So does that mean the threat is over?
No. The experts that I've spoken with
told me that these killer bees
don't fly after dark.
So, with temps dropping,
it's likely that they've
just bedded down for the night.
- Thank you for that...
- [KNOCK AT DOOR]
- [MADDIE] Come in.
- [DOOR OPENS]
Okay, we've got mushroom,
eggplant and peppers,
and one Denny special.
- Triple pepperoni.
- [CHUCKLES]
You know, one of these weeks,
you guys are gonna have to let us cook.
Oh, only if you let us do the dishes.
- Oh, sold.
- [LAUGHS]
Jee, Mara, who's gonna help me
clear the table?
[SIGHS] There's my girl.
- [CHUCKLES] Hi.
- Mom,
Mama, we made a Lego racetrack.
Then we smashed it.
- Oh!
- Scourgify!
Evanesco!
- [CHIMNEY] Yes.
- What?
Are they speaking in tongues?
Harry Potter spells.
Chim and Mara are obsessed.
So, how did the meeting go
with the new foster attorney?
Great. Great. She's a real powerhouse,
and she says we have a strong case
- to get our foster license back.
- Yep.
And the magical words
"Councilwoman Ortiz"
have no power over her.
Well, that's great. So,
do you have a court date yet?
No, we're still in the early days,
but we do have another
meeting with her on Friday.
Baby, we might need to push that
to next week.
I don't think Gerrard's gonna be
open to me taking an hour off my shift.
- Your boss is a jerk.
- [SIGHS]
That's one word for what he is.
So, he punishes me
for thinking on my feet,
and then I hear him
on the phone to the chief,
and he's taking credit for my idea.
Yep. Sounds like Gerrard.
Okay, that looks great.
He's gonna love it. Put these on.
- Mm-hmm.
- Get in position.
Okay.
[CHUCKLES] I'm, uh, I'm sorry,
did you want the red one?
Has anyone ever told you
you are a vision in a cone?
[EXCITED CHATTER OVER LAPTOP]
[EDDIE] Hey, birthday boy!
Wow, Chris. 14.
Yeah, it feels like you
were 13 when? Yesterday?
I, um, miss you, buddy.
Uh-huh.
Well, I heard you got my gift,
but I, uh,
got one more surprise for you.
[BLOWS NOISEMAKER]
[BUCK AND TOMMY] Surprise!
[LAUGHS]
[CHOPPY AUDIO ON LAPTOP]
Come on, really, Chris?
Oh, I'm sorry, honey.
I think, I think the thing froze.
Not like it mattered much anyways.
[HELENA] Well, I don't know,
it seemed like it went better
than last time, right?
[EDDIE] Mm-hmm. I guess. I got a whole
"uh-huh" out of him.
[HELENA] Aw, well, don't give up.
He'll-he'll come around.
But look at him,
look at him with his-his-his
new friends, right?
Yeah. Who are all these kids, anyway?
Um, well, a few are from
the, uh, the pool club
that we've been going to,
and then, uh, there's Izzy
and Deana are from down the street.
The pool club?
Yeah. He loves the water so much.
You know, your dad and I are thinking
about putting in a pool of our own.
Wow. Great.
[CROWD OVER LAPTOP]
♪ Happy birthday... ♪
[HELENA] Oh, honey, they're
singing. I got to go. Mwah.
Bye.
Oh, wait, can you...? [SIGHS]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday ♪
♪ Dear Christopher. ♪
[SHEILA] The party is
going to be perfection.
How many RSVPs?
Um, about half the list.
- What?
- Uh, but these influencer types,
they're so last-minute. They'll show.
Be honest,
am I an idiot for spending
my entire divorce settlement
launching a boutique fragrance line?
Of course not. What?
Thank you.
I am so glad I didn't
replace you with an AI.
Thanks?
[SIGHS]
You're right.
Tomorrow is going to be flawless.
- [BEE BUZZING]
- [TORI GIGGLES]
[BEES BUZZING]
♪ Be my little baby bumblebee ♪
♪ Buzz around, buzz around... ♪
[GLASS CLINKING]
[TORI] Well, hello.
Thank you all for coming
to the exclusive debut
of my new fragrance:
Tori, by Tori.
With zingy lemongrass...
[SNIFFS] Mmm!
And hints of cassis,
this eau de parfum
will sweep you to the tropics and back.
Who wants the first spritz?
Yes! [LAUGHS]
- Young lady.
- Oh, okay.
Whoever you are, you're in for a treat.
What's your name, sweetie?
- Uh, Sh-Sheila.
- Well, Sheila,
get ready for an instant vacay.
All it takes is one pump.
Maybe two, just for fun.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, my God!
[SCREAMS]
- [BEES BUZZING]
- [GUESTS SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
[MAN] Get inside over there.
Head to cover.
[SCREAMING]
_
Ma'am, can you get everyone inside?
Not everyone. My assistant Sheila,
she jumped in the water, and
they started hovering, and then,
every time she comes up for air,
- they sting her.
- Okay, they will wait over water.
We need to get Sheila to the shallow end
- and have her stay underwater.
- What?
How is she supposed
to breathe underwater?
You said you were
at a garden party, right?
Betting you have a garden hose.
Eyes up.
We got a drowning vic somewhere to find.
Thank God. She's over here.
Where?
With the rest of this.
- How long has she been down there?
- About 25 minutes?
[HEN] We can't just pull
her up into the swarm.
We got to move the bees.
Smoke worked last time.
[GERRARD] No more freelancing, Buckley.
Get inside, give out waters,
check for boo-boos.
Let the grown-ups handle this.
Sir, yes, sir.
Here you go.
Water.
[WOMAN] I got stung seven times.
God, I am never going
to another perfume launch.
Okay? I don't care
what's in the swag bag.
Uh, I'm sorry.
Did you say "perfume launch"?
Yeah.
Who was wearing the perfume?
[COUGHS, CHOKES]
[CHIMNEY] Hey, guys.
I think they found a loophole.
- Cap! Cap!
- Buck,
- where's your bee hood?
- [BUCK] I-I have an idea.
If I may, sir.
Am I gonna like it?
Well, uh... [SIGHS] he probably won't.
So, bees are attracted to floral scents,
but other smells,
like banana, make them mad.
Well, this has both.
[SIGHS] Okay, but why
does it have to be me?
You're the fastest runner.
And you smell wonderful, by the way.
Han, they take the bait,
you dive in ASAP.
Copy that, Cap.
Godspeed, Diaz.
[SIGHS]
[RIMSKY-KORSAKOV'S "FLIGHT
OF THE BUMBLEBEE" PLAYING]
It's okay, Eddie, you got it.
No.
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Go! Go!
- Not yet. Not yet.
Now, let's go.
[HEN] Come on. We got you.
Aah!
Right here is good.
Looks like she's been stung
a thousand times.
How's her airways?
[SHEILA WHEEZING]
As swollen as you'd expect.
We're gonna have to do a trach.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Here.
Do a bougie. This much trauma,
I don't want to cut her open
unless we have to.
She's bradycardic.
Her pulse is 50s and dropping.
I'm pushing atropine.
[CHIMNEY] All this bee venom,
it's shutting down her organs.
And these stingers are releasing
venom by the second.
It'll take hours for us
to get 'em all out.
She'll be dead before that.
Unless we can get 'em all out at once.
How would we do that?
Duct tape. They say it fixes everything.
- I can't believe that worked.
- Told you.
All right, I'm inflating
the cuff, securing the airway.
[HEN] O2 sat's rising.
Pulse stabilizing.
Sheila, I am so sorry.
I'm the worst boss ever.
Oh, you'd be surprised.
[GERRARD OVER RADIO]
Buckley, what's the holdup?
Okay, almost done, Cap. Hey, you ready?
For what?
For Monty.
- Who's Monty?
- [UNZIPS TENT]
Monty Moore, beekeeper to the stars.
Dispatch sent me.
Arms up, please. This won't hurt a bit.
Been shot before. I'm pretty
sure I can handle this.
I was talking to the bees, sir.
[VACUUM WHIRRING]
A couple more.
Got 'em.
That ought to do it.
That's it?
We beat the bees.
Well, I got about one or two
hundred thousand in here.
Great, just 14.8 million on the loose.
Great news, Cap.
Patient is stable.
We'll hit up the O.R. for observation,
but we got her out in time.
You want a trophy?
Get in the rig.
[SIGHS]
Buzzkill.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[DENNIS] I wanted you to know
that I never forgot about him.
I never forgot about
what I did that night.
Me neither.
You spent months
afraid you'd be recognized?
I spent years
searching every face I saw,
wondering, was that man the one?
Was his face the last thing
that Emmett saw
before he died?
[SNIFFLES]
You have no idea
what decades of not knowing
does to a person.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[GUARD] Stand by for open on Grid Three.
Grid Three, open up.
[DOOR CLANGS OPEN]
Get changed.
We got a flight to catch.
Thank you for coming to get me.
I appreciate you saying yes.
I assume you're wondering
why I asked for you.
Crossed my mind.
Two reasons.
First, I wanted you to hear it from me.
That I made a deal.
That I'm getting out.
I'm going back to my family.
And I don't... I don't know
if I-I still owe a debt to society,
but I know I owe one to you.
And I owe one to Emmett's mom.
Please stop.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[DENNIS] What? What's happening?
Looks like we're getting pulled over.
Don't stop.
What?
Don't stop. Don't trust this.
I mean it.
Whoever it is,
they're just gonna try
and take me from you.
Prison made you paranoid, Dennis? Relax.
Call it in. Please.
[EXHALES]
No bars.
Sit tight.
Athena Grant,
- LAPD.
- Yeah, Sergeant,
sorry to rush up on you like that.
Was worried I wouldn't catch you.
Uh, Fredericks, U.S. Attorney's Office.
Afraid I got orders to take
custody of your prisoner.
Our office would like
to depose Mr. Jenkins
before he flies off to La-La.
You don't say.
Yeah. That him there?
Yeah, unless, uh, I picked up
the wrong prisoner.
You got paperwork?
Yeah.
Makes me sick,
cutting a deal with a cop-killer.
Son of a bitch should rot for life.
All right. Looks official, all right.
Just one problem.
Yeah?
No one sent it to me.
Well, it's hard
to get reception out here.
Probably come through
when you get into town.
Well, then I'd better get
back on the road with him.
My state, my jurisdiction.
My prisoner.
I signed for him.
[LAUGHS]
Hey, I don't have time for this.
Like you didn't have time
to put the right state seal
on that forgery?
Don't even.
Hands on your head.
Who are you?
What do you want with my prisoner?
You're not gonna tell me?
You ever seen Thelma & Louise?
Don't worry,
as soon as I get service,
I'll call in and let 'em know
that you're out here.
Or maybe I'll wait till we get to La-La.
[DENNIS] The second reason
I asked for you to pick me up
is because you're
the only cop I can trust.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Someone wants me dead.
They're gonna have to get in line.
I don't think anyone else
followed us here.
[DENNIS] Well, how many people
knew you were coming to get me?
More than two.
Well, they gonna be waiting on us
when we get off that plane.
No, they're not. We're changing flights.
Come on.
Hey, wait a minute. You don't...
you don't think this looks strange?
[HANDCUFFS RATTLE]
You happy now?
Thank you.
Come on.
To L.A.? I don't have anything.
Burbank, Long Beach.
We're not picky.
I have a flight to Honolulu
with a stopover at LAX, but...
- But?
- It's gonna be tight.
You may not make it
before the doors close.
We'll take it.
And I'm checking a firearm as well.
Said his name's Fredericks,
U.S. Attorney.
He give a first name?
He tried to shoot me
before we got to that.
Elaine, somebody does not want this man
appearing before a grand jury.
And you left this Agent Fredericks
in his car's trunk?
Left on the side of the road.
I imagine he's pretty toasty by now.
Send me the location.
I'll speak to someone at Phoenix PD,
make sure they get him out and hold him
until we can figure out what's going on.
Get yourself back to L.A. in one piece.
Okay. I'll call you when we land.
Who's that?
My captain.
[BELL RINGS]
Hollywood glamour, eh, Captain Nash?
It's pretty hard to complain.
And yet something tells me
you'd rather not be here.
Well, I was assigned here,
so I'm on duty.
The fire department's
run out of fire stations?
Something like that.
So, the, uh, grips, they tell me
that you're a bit of a hero.
Sunken Ferris wheel?
Or was it a cruise ship?
Well, both, actually.
So the rumors are true.
You're an LAFD legend.
I'm a civil servant, still am.
You know De Niro?
He trained with the real
Jake LaMotta for Raging Bull.
I've-I've never actually seen it.
You're my LaMotta, Captain Nash.
I'm gonna study you tip to tail.
Why?
Because, from where I'm sitting,
your job's the glamour one.
Yeah?
Ah.
Think I finally got
all the bee guts off the windshield.
Same with the gauges.
Oddly, I crave honey.
[HEN AND BUCK SIGH]
Think we'll have to do it
all over in 20 minutes?
[BUCK] Nah, the heat
should make 'em fly higher.
Maddie said dispatch
hasn't gotten a call in hours.
[SIGHING] Okay.
[HAMMERS POUNDING]
Wow.
Do those guys ever take a hammer break?
[SAW BUZZING]
Yeah, but only when
they pick up the saw.
[GERRARD] Buckwad.
You missed a spot.
Uh, where?
There.
When you're done,
I want to lick the bumper
and taste chrome.
Yes, sir.
What, i-is this 'cause
of my perfume idea?
No, it's because you jump chain
of command every damn call.
You think you're something, huh?
With your tattoos
and your broody little pout.
[CHUCKLES] Uh...
m-my pout, sir?
Four decades in the fire service,
you think I don't know
what insolence looks like?
Do I need to remind you
who's captain of this firehouse?
I'm shocked you haven't washed out.
You disrespectful...
[ECHOING] Or is your skull
too thick for that to sink in?
- ..lollygagging...
- Let the grown-ups handle this one.
Disgrace to the uniform.
At best, a work in progress.
Do it again.
Fall in line, Bucko.
- Unsatisfactory.
- Believe you me, you're gonna be
- in for a world of hurt.
- Buckley,
- what the hell are you doing?
- [EDDIE] You got to stop letting
this guy get under your skin
- like this, Buck.
- [GERRARD] Give out waters.
What's the matter, Buckley?
- Do it again.
- Want me to pat you
- on the back like your daddy?
- Do you want a hug?
- Disrespectful.
- Do it again.
- [CREWMAN] Aah!
- [BUCK GRUNTS]
[CLANGING]
Whoa.
You saved him.
[CHIMNEY] Or maybe killed him.
Get the leads on him.
I'll get the Lifepak.
Okay, you sit tight.
I'm gonna talk to the captain,
make sure LAPD is at the gate for us.
Ma'am, we just began our descent.
If you could retake your seat...
I need to speak to the pilot.
It's urgent.
I can't let you in there.
The phone is fine.
This is Captain Dominguez.
Captain, there is a police sergeant here
who'd like to speak to you.
All right. I was coming out anyways.
[COPILOT] Left turn 30 degrees...
[COMPUTER]
Traffic. Traffic. Climb. Climb.
- Pull up!
- Pulling up!
Traffic. Traffic. Climb. Climb.
Oh, no!
[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
- Synced and corrected by synk -
- www.addic7ed.com -