[VICTORIA] Previously on Station 19...
[NATASHA] Congratulations, Herrera.
You are officially the
new captain of Station 19.
I started researching IVF.
Yes, let's do it.
- Is this a breakup?
- You want it to be a breakup?
- [VICTORIA] This...
- [THEO] Bye.
[JACK] Oh! Sorry.
[SCREAMING]
- [GRUNTS]
- [SCREAMS]
[SOBBING, CRYING]
- I wanna love you back.
- [GASPS]
- [TRAVIS] Jack? Jack!
- [VICTORIA] Gibson?
- [ANDY] Jack? Jack?
- [VICTORIA] Yeah.
[BEN] Jack. Jack.
- [FIRE ALARM BLARING]
- [JACK] We gotta get out of here.
- Come on.
- [DISPATCH] Emergency traffic.
We're in operational retreat.
All units, exit immediately.
[JACK] Move it. Come on, guys. Move it.
Seattle Fire! Everyone out!
[SYMPHONIC MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
[DISPATCH] Gibson. Gibson, do you copy?
Evacuate now. Structure's unstable.
Somebody's still in here, Captain.
Hey, I hear music.
- [PERSON COUGHING]
- [FIRST ALARM CONTINUES BLARING]
[SYMPHONIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[GASPS]
[MUSIC WINDS DOWN]
[REPORTER ON TV] The investigation
continues inside this ballroom
where only 36 hours
ago, a floor collapsed
costing several lives, including that of
former Seattle Fire Chief Michael Dixon.
Several other injured party-goers
were rushed to Grey
Sloan Memorial Hospital.
Among them, embattled current
Fire Chief Natasha Ross,
who recently admitted
to having an affair
with a rank-and-file
firefighter she promoted.
A violation of department policy.
Authorities say the cause of
the floor collapse is still...
[TV CLICKS OFF]
People died,
but let's not forget the
embattled chief and her sex scandal.
You wish we hadn't
gone public at the ball?
People already knew we were
together. We just confirmed it.
Hey, wh-where are you going?
I'm going to the mayor's
office to fight for my job.
You need to heal, all right?
You're not Wonder Woman.
Keep the leg where it is.
And the mayor's not gonna
fire you, not after what happened.
[NATASHA] I look weak.
The floor collapsed.
It wasn't your fault.
You know that doesn't matter.
People like us, we
can't show any weakness.
And as soon as we do, they get rid of us
and then they say, "See,
they can't handle it."
You keep spinning out like that,
you gonna blow an
aneurysm and have a stroke.
- You want some ice chips?
- I'm not having a baby, Sully.
- [ROBERT LAUGHS]
- God. [LAUGHS]
Fresh cup of coffee, maybe?
All right.
Pretty please and thank you.
I got you.
[DOOR SHUTS]
[STAFF ON PA] Dr. Watkins,
report to pediatrics.
Dr. Watkins to pediatrics.
Oh, how is he? How'd it go?
We removed a piece of his
skull to get at the hematoma,
and we evacuated it successfully.
Fortunately, there was no
significant brain swelling,
so we were able to replace the
piece of skull that we removed.
Okay. So-So he's gonna be all right?
Well, it's too early to tell.
I will know more when he wakes up.
He took a pretty hard hit.
His body needs time to recover.
Thank you.
[STAFF ON PA] paging Dr. Brown.
Neonatal unit, paging Dr. Brown.
[SIGHS]
[JACK] Aw, you do care.
But maybe right now is not the
best time to be crying, hey, Cap?
You have a team to lead.
Buck up.
- Synced and corrected by ChrisKe -
-- for www.addic7ed.com --
[PA BEEPS]
- [STAFF ON PA] Dr. Kale to...
- [SIGHS]
[VICTORIA] Hey, you talked to Kate?
Briefly. She's waiting
on a neurology consult.
- Neurology?
- Her doctor's being extra careful.
Then when if that checks
out, the department signs off,
- she'll be back to wreaking havoc...
- [PHONE BUZZING]
- at stations all over Seattle in no time.
- [CHUCKLES]
It's chaos. It's Chaos
Kate, not Havoc Kate.
[CHUCKLES] Yeah. Well,
either way, brace yourself.
Hey, Roz, what's up?
No, no, no, we're
still waiting to hear.
How are the kids?
[THEO] Hey.
It's weird to be
on Crisis One together.
- [CHUCKLES] Because we broke up?
- Yeah.
If you want me to ask Herrera to
sub somebody in for me, I will.
It's a risk we took when
we decided to date a coworker.
We're adults. We can do our jobs.
Jack is out of surgery. I
just spoke to the surgeon.
[VICTORIA] How is he?
It went well. There's
no brain swelling.
- [VICTORIA SIGHS] Okay.
- [BEN] Gibson?
That's a good sign. Did
they leave the skull open?
Nope. Put it back together.
Okay. That is a really good sign.
- [GURGLING]
- [WHISPERING] I know.
I know. I know.
[SIGHING] Hey.
[COOING CONTINUES]
He has no idea his
mom didn't make it.
You did the best that you could.
It feels so random that the-the
floor crushed under our feet
and now some of us are gone.
But some of us are still here.
It just does not feel fair.
But this has cleared up some things.
- About?
- Us.
[CARINA SIGHS]
You weren't clear about us before?
Okay, so I know I said I
could, and I thought I could,
but I can't live in
your apartment anymore.
There are too many
painful memories there.
- Okay.
- Okay, so I thought,
why don't we start fresh? In a house.
I'll be starting IVF soon,
and I want a place
where we can build a life
for us and our new family.
And a garden where I can
plant origano and basilico
and rosmarino.
And a backyard with space to work out.
And a table outside to have
friends over when it's nice.
- Our house.
- Our.
- House.
- Yeah.
Our home.
- I'm in.
- [WHISPERS] Oh, my God.
Okay. [KISSES, GIGGLES]
If there's significant
brain swelling,
they have to wait for it to go down.
- [ANDY] You okay?
- [THEO] Yeah.
[SIGHS] Look, I know how
it feels to be passed over
for a leadership position.
Heck, it is what it is.
All right? What do you want me to say?
Look, I don't expect you to like it,
but I need to know that we're a team.
- [ON RADIO] Crisis One...
- And that I can count on you...
- [VICTORIA] Ruiz.
- ...to have my back, just like
- I did when we were at 23.
- Hey, let's go.
Can I?
Yes, Captain.
- [TRAVIS EXHALES]
- [ELI] Hey, there.
I thought I showered fast,
but you do the three-minute wash and go.
[CHUCKLES] Yeah, sorry.
Don't want to be late.
Got a huge meeting about
staffing department heads.
Do you think after what happened
he's still gonna replace Ross?
I honestly couldn't
say. It's complicated.
Anyway, don't spend your
day off thinking about work.
Says the guy who'll be
at work thinking about you.
- Mmm. I like that.
- Mmm.
- See you tonight.
- Mmm. You will.
Be good.
[EMPLOYEE 1] Look around you
and ground yourself in reality.
- [EMPLOYEE 2] Oh, my gosh.
- [EMPLOYEE 1] I'm sorry.
[EMPLOYEE 2] What are you even saying?
[EMPLOYEE 1] Please.
Why are you doing this?
[EMPLOYEE 2] Because you lied!
- [KNOCKS ON DOOR]
- [EMPLOYEE 2] What?
- We're closed.
- Okay. Seattle Fire.
We, uh... We got a call
about a disturbance.
Help us! She blocked all the exits.
[EMPLOYEE 3] That stuff
she's holding, are explosives.
She's a disgruntled employee.
She's trying to blow this place up.
[EMPLOYEE 2] Yeah, I was pretty
gruntled until you and Sanjay
- lied to all of us gathered here.
- I'm gonna call PD.
Yeah, we might need the bomb squad,
but I don't wanna spook her, so...
I'll tell them no sirens and
to standby until we need them.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I'm from the fire department.
Okay, my name's Vic.
- What's your name?
- [EMPLOYEE 2] Get lost, lady.
- There's no fire here.
- Her name is Phyllis Myers.
Okay, thank you. I'm-I'm
just here to talk, Phyllis.
Can you tell me what
you have in your hand?
It's antifreeze.
[PHYLLIS] You are smarter
than everybody says, Kevin.
So I guess you know that
when I mix it with this,
I get a wildly explosive compound.
- You wanna see me win the science fair?
- [ALL] Phyllis! [SCREAMING]
[VICTORIA] Phyllis. Hey, hey,
hey, talk to me. Talk to me.
- [EMPLOYEE 4] She's gonna blow us all up!
- [VICTORIA] Talk to me.
Your coworkers, they look pretty
scared, so why don't you just tell me?
Tell me why you're so upset.
Because these dicks
stole my life's work!
[JACK] Don't look too good, do I?
Get out of my head, Jack.
[MAYA] Hey.
I heard it went well.
That's positive.
Yeah. If he would just
wake up. [INHALES DEEPLY]
[MAYA] He will.
Can I say something as your friend?
Oh. [CHUCKLES] This ought to be good.
It's natural to be stressed
in this situation.
First shift in charge. Jack...
The last day and a half of chaos.
Emotions can rise and
get the best of you.
- She's saying you can't cry.
- [ANDY] Hmm.
- I'm not gonna cry.
- [MAYA] It's not fair, I know.
But as a woman in charge,
you have the weight
of every woman in the
department on your shoulders.
That's what you said to
her when she was captain.
It's different now. [STAMMERS]
We have a woman as chief.
Yeah, but for how much longer?
If Osman fires her,
a thousand bucks says he
appoints a good old boy,
and we're back to the way it was.
It's not enough to be
strong. You have to be tough.
We don't have the luxury
of screwing up, not even once.
Hate to admit it, but she's right.
[MAYA] I'm just down
the hall if you need me.
[ANDY] Thank you.
[STAFF ON PA] Nurse Palmer to
room 1197. Nurse Palmer, room 1...
I spent my whole life working in tech.
And at every job I've had,
douche-bags like this poach
my work and take the credit.
[VICTORIA] Hey, Phyllis.
Phyllis, what do you do here?
I'm a chemical engineer.
Okay, cool. What do you engineer?
We're developing a low-cost
technology to purify water.
- Wow.
- Not everybody is as lucky as we are.
A quarter of the world doesn't have
a reliable source of drinking water.
Okay, and that's... Climate
change is making it worse,
I'm guessing.
- A-plus, Fyra Banks.
- Okay.
They said they would patent
the technology we developed,
- but leave it open.
- We never said that.
- Yes, you did, Sanjay!
- [EMPLOYEE 4] Shut up, Sanjay.
You're gonna make
her spill that stuff.
- You mean this stuff?
- [VICTORIA] Uh... You know what?
Phyllis. Phyllis, what do you mean?
What do you mean leave it open?
[PHYLLIS] It means that anyone
can use it without paying for it,
like people in underdeveloped countries.
- [VICTORIA] Okay.
- But an hour ago,
I find out that the patent is closed
and that they filed it in their names,
so that they could get rich quick.
- Okay.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- Did you think I wouldn't find out?
- [VICTORIA] Phyllis...
My partner's trying to de-escalate,
but the subject has explosive chemicals.
Sirens and lights
might cause her to act.
[DISPATCH] Copy that, Lieutenant Ruiz.
Notifying Seattle PD.
All ground floor exits are locked.
No exterior stairwells or access
to the higher floors either.
Phyllis, hey, you know what, I'm...
I'm... I'm so sorry that that happened.
Nobody likes to be deceived.
[SANJAY] Nobody deceived anybody...
Sir, I am talking to Phyllis right now.
[PHYLLIS] They just wanted to use me.
I have been working on cheap, scalable
water purification for 30 years.
- You know, I'm glad somebody has been.
- He has too.
- [VICTORIA] Okay.
- And him.
And him. They lied to all of us.
Why aren't you pissed
off about it, you sheep?
Stand up!
Travis.
It's lovely to see
you. Come in. Come in.
Ooh.
- [DOOR SHUTS]
- People have been dropping by
all day. [LAUGHS]
Actually, you just
missed some firefighters.
Although, you probably wouldn't
know them, they were Dick's age.
- My mom made this.
- Oh!
She's a better cook than I am.
[LAUGHS] How sweet of her. Oh, okay.
Well, why don't you, uh, set it
over there with the rest of the food?
And please help yourself to
a plate. There's so much.
And I'm almost done with
the funeral director, okay?
Okay.
So as I was saying,
he was partial to Beethoven's Eroica,
and, um, the second
movement is a funeral march,
but I don't know, it's
just so bombastic, you know?
Let's go with the
Mahler. It was his favorite.
Springsteen was his favorite.
Hi.
Yeah, I can do two o'clock.
Will you confirm with them?
- [ROBERT SIGHS]
- Thank you.
What are you doing?
My job. I've got my laptop here,
might as well go over some paperwork.
You're supposed to be resting.
I'm still the chief.
There's work to do,
and doing it is the only way I
can fight to keep my job right now.
Thank you, my love.
Your work ethic has
never been the issue.
It's not gonna be the issue now.
I don't want Mayor Osman to say,
"I'm not firing her
because she broke the rules,
I'm firing her because
she didn't do her job." No.
While you're in the hospital,
you think he would do that?
[MAYOR OSMAN] Is this a bad time?
- [ROBERT] Mr. Mayor.
- Mayor Osman.
[MAYOR OSMAN] They letting
you out of here anytime soon?
Not without a walking boot.
I was hoping to have a word with
you if you're feeling up for it.
I am.
Can you excuse us, Lieutenant Sullivan?
- May I? [CLEARS THROAT]
- Absolutely.
[DOOR SHUTS]
- That's why I wanted to send her ahead.
- Of course. Right.
[STAFF ON PA] to pediatrics. Nurse...
- [GRUNTS]
- To pediatrics.
- Hey.
- [ROBERT] Hey. [SIGHS]
- How's the chief?
- [SIGHS] In with the mayor.
He kicked me out.
Oh.
[INHALES DEEPLY] Yeah. I think...
I think he might cut her loose.
- At the hospital? That's cold.
- And stupid.
She's the best chief
the city has had in decades.
He's gonna fire her over a rule
that has nothing to do
with how she does her job?
It's just... It's not right.
- It's politics.
- [SCOFFS]
[EXHALES] You gonna be okay?
It's not me who's
gonna lose his job.
No. I mean, are you gonna be okay
knowing that you're the
reason she's losing hers?
I get it. You just
found out an hour ago,
and it's fresh, and
your blood is boiling.
But do you really think you're
gonna be this mad tomorrow?
- Or-Or a week from now?
- Yes.
Angry enough to blow
up this entire building
with your... your colleagues in it?
Because they're people too.
Just like the people
you're trying to help.
Maybe they've been overlooked like
you have. Maybe they're hurting too.
Don't you think that
maybe there's a way
for all of you to get your due
without literally blowing everything up?
Who's that? The bad cop?
No. He... We are not
cops. He is my partner.
No, I'm Theo, and
we're also paramedics.
Now, you can stay where you are,
and Vic will stay with
you as long as you want,
but I see your security
guard has a cut on his head.
[EMPLOYEE 4] He fell trying to stop her.
And there's a lady over there
hyperventilating from the stress.
I-If you let them out, I can
make sure everyone's okay
while you and Vic keep talking.
You're not coming in here.
All right, Phyllis. Do you think
they're gonna change their minds
and open the patent under threat?
- Phyllis.
- [EMPLOYEE 4 CRYING]
Phyllis, I know you think that
we... we're nothing alike...
but you know, there are
probably as many women
in the fire service as there were
in tech when you first started.
Look, I know what it's like
to have to shout to be heard.
Your coworkers are terrified.
And, honestly, so am I,
because if you mix
those chemicals together,
I am standing in front of a glass wall.
Okay? But I don't think
you wanna hurt anybody.
I think maybe you might not have
thought this all the way through
and now you're out of moves.
But if you put those chemicals down
and you let your coworkers go,
I promise I will stay with you
and I will try to help
you find a way out.
Phyllis, let me help you.
Let me help you, Phyllis. Please.
[VICTORIA] Okay.
[EXHALES]
[EXHALES, CRIES]
[EMMETT] The food in Florence
is even better than people say.
I swear I gained, like, ten pounds
the first month that I was there.
Well, you don't look like it.
Oh. Well, it's because I found a gym
the second month I was there.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
[KITTY] Funeral director is gone.
He had such a lovely
bedside manner, you know?
Or whatever you call
it in that business.
You seem to be holding up well.
You mean considering
you killed my husband?
Mom.
Did you try the coffee cake?
One of the ladies from
the auxiliary made it.
It's good.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
No. It's okay. It's okay.
I know she's not herself today.
I was beginning to wonder if she
even remembered what happened.
What did happen?
She said you were with him.
[SIGHS]
He was under a slab of concrete.
We worked to get it off of him.
He was calm.
He talked about you.
What did he say?
He said now that you live in Europe,
you don't bring boys home anymore.
To me, it seemed... like
he missed you, Emmett.
Like he wished he would
have had more time...
Okay.
- [THEO CLEARS THROAT]
- [VICTORIA] You go first.
All right, everyone. This
way, if you need some help.
[VICTORIA] Watch your feet.
[THEO] Let's get you checked out.
- [VICTORIA] Are you okay?
- [SECURITY GUARD] Thank you.
[THEO] Just step right here.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[SIREN APPROACHING]
- Did you call the police?
- [VICTORIA] No, I didn't.
Phyllis, I did not call the police.
Oh, they're coming. You're
going to jail, you crazy bitch.
[VICTORIA] Hey, wait. [GROANS, STRAINS]
[SIREN CONTINUES]
[KEVIN] Oh, my God.
She's gonna do it.
God, she's gonna do it.
- Sanjay, come on. Come on!
- Kevin, no!
No, no. Stop, stop,
stop! No, no, no. Stop!
- [BEN] Marsha, I'm sorry.
- Why didn't you call me sooner?
I was going crazy. Calling his
phone, calling all the hospitals.
- You're right. I should have...
- I-I called his sister.
Brooke? He barely knows her.
I'm more family than she is.
You call me when he's
not answering his phone.
- I expected more from you.
- You're absolutely right, Marsha.
- I'm... very sorry.
- [SOBBING]
Oh, my poor boy.
Well, I'm sure he's gonna be
glad you're here when he wakes up.
[MARSHA SIGHS] I'm here now.
I’m sorry I took so long.
[SOBS]
[SANJAY] Hold up. Hold
up. Hold up. Hold up.
[KEVIN] She's gonna
destroy the prototype.
Guys. Guys, stop!
- This isn't safe!
- [SANJAY] Take it easy, man.
- She's probably headed for the lab.
- We can't let her.
Let me talk to her first!
I'd duck if I were you.
[KEVIN GRUNTS]
[EXPLOSION]
- [ONLOOKER GASPS]
- Hughes, what's your status?
Hughes, what's your status?
[VICTORIA ON RADIO] Explosion and fire
on the third floor.
[PANTS] I'm uninjured, but...
Moving three civilians to cover.
[THEO ON RADIO] Copy. Calling backup.
Dispatch, this is Lieutenant Ruiz
requesting full company 19 to the
business park at 1 Alder Court.
Stay low. Stay low. Move to
that open room. Go, go, go!
[BREATHES HEAVILY] Phyllis?
- [COUGHS] Phyllis, come on.
- Okay.
Let's get you out
of the smoke. I got you.
Let's get you away from
the smoke, okay? Come on.
- [PHYLLIS] Ow!
- It's okay.
[SIREN WAILING]
Four minutes out, 19.
I want everything tight
and everyone communicating.
[DISPATCH ON RADIO]
Copy that. Comms open.
I spoke to Warren before
we left the hospital.
He said Osman was talking to the
chief. Do you know about what?
Whatever it was, they didn't
let me stick around to hear it.
- Do you think that...
- I don't know, Captain.
[COUGHING]
[VICTORIA] I got you,
Phyllis. I got you.
- Sanjay, move that table.
- [PHYLLIS GRUNTS]
All right. Kevin, shut the door.
- [VICTORIA GRUNTS]
- [PHYLLIS GROANS]
- Okay. Yeah, you're okay. You're okay.
- [PHYLLIS] Ow! [GRUNTS]
Sanjay, give me your shirt
to stop this bleeding.
Blowing up the servers is way
worse than hitting the lab.
Why do you think I did it, dumbass?
- You're gonna pay for this.
- You shouldn't have lied to me!
Stop! Now is not the time! We need
to find a way out of here. Okay?
Why isn't the fire
suppression system kicking in?
Blast must've knocked it out.
[VICTORIA] My team will be here soon.
I didn't... I didn't
mean for this to happen.
- Oh, well.
- I just...
When that smug bastard started
talking about the cops coming,
I just blacked out with rage.
- [COMPUTER BEEPS]
- [VICTORIA] Phyllis, hold this.
Hold this on real tight. Okay?
I just...
I'm just so tired of people
using me to make them rich.
Lean up. Come on, Phyllis.
I just... I wanted to put
good in the world, and now...
- Oh, my God.
- [VICTORIA] Hey, Phyllis.
Phyllis, we just need
to get out of here now.
Okay? I hear you, but
we have to focus on that.
- You were there.
- [CARINA] I'm sorry?
I'm the chef from the ball.
- Right. In the kitchen, yeah.
- I'm Wolf.
Carina DeLuca. I remember you now.
Um, are you here to see the baby?
Yeah, I just saw him. Poor little guy.
He's in perfect health.
He should be discharged soon.
Yeah, I know. I'm...
I'm gonna adopt him.
- Wow. [CHUCKLES]
- [CHUCKLES]
Yeah, Nanette was already
looking for families,
but, you know, they won't
know anything about her.
I can tell them about what
a great person she was.
- You were close?
- Uh, worked together
most nights for a few years.
She said that she hoped
that whoever got him
would name him Liam.
He was her favorite
member of One Direction.
- [CHUCKLES]
- Okay.
Yeah. So that's his name, Liam.
"My son."
Sounds weird, but
I'll get used to it.
I-I think she'd be really,
really happy that he's with me.
I can see she meant a lot to you.
- Yeah.
- Mm-hmm.
Wish me luck.
Good luck.
[FIREFIGHTER 1 TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[FIREFIGHTER 2] It's on the other side!
All right. We got Hughes
and three civilians
sheltering in place on the third floor.
Bishop, Cutler, find us
access to the third floor.
Sullivan, Larsson,
get the aerial up to the
third floor for a rescue.
Wiggins, Galarza, Pratt, Boyd,
run some lines up to the third
floor and knock down that fire.
Bottles and masks on. Go!
[ANDY ON RADIO] Hughes, this is
Captain Herrera. What's your 20?
Uh, we are in a closed monitor
room on the third floor.
Southwest side.
Egress is blocked by
fire. Windows are sealed.
Narrow balcony outside.
Yeah. Ruiz checked that out.
It-It goes around the building,
but it's not a way down.
- [SANJAY] Oh, no.
- [VICTORIA] What?
The servers have backup
lithium batteries.
When they heat up, they
release a toxic gas.
- Room's not airtight.
- [SANJAY] They could explode.
Okay. Are they off-gassing now?
Not yet, but the temps are creeping up.
- Wait. Are we gonna die here?
- Isn't that what you wanted?
[VICTORIA] Hey! Stop,
stop. Okay. Uh, Kevin,
find anything you can to stuff
in the spaces around the door
to keep the gas out.
All right? Anything.
I'm talking fabric, paper, whatever.
Sanjay, keep an eye on those monitors,
and let me know if we get
in the danger zone. Okay?
Captain, we need to get
out of here right now.
Why is the aerial not up
to the third floor yet?
We don't have the clearance to
move the rig in the right position.
The buildings are too tight.
We use the rescue cushion,
if they can all jump.
- If they can't, she can push them.
- Get ready and stand by.
[ANDY ON RADIO] Hughes,
we're getting a rescue cushion
set up below your window.
Okay. Our best chance to get out of
here is to jump to the rescue cushion
- they'll set up below. Yeah?
- Okay. Okay.
If that's the only
option, I'll do it.
Okay. Phyllis?
- I can do it.
- [VICTORIA] Okay.
All civilians physically
able and ready to jump.
[ANDY ON RADIO] Sullivan, you're on.
[ROBERT ON RADIO] Copy, Captain.
You know, I'm not surprised
Gibson never changed his
emergency contact info.
The man is allergic
to official paperwork.
It's like his kryptonite.
He was driving around for four
months on an expired license.
I said, "Jack, all you gotta
do is fill out the form,
- and drop it in the mail."
- Or do it online.
You don't even have to go to the DMV.
He just didn't
wanna do it. [CHUCKLES]
Oh, and don't even
bring up medical forms.
Yeah, when we started
the clinic at the station,
that was one of his non-negotiables.
No forms of any kind, no white coats.
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS] I apologize for
being so irritable...
- Oh.
- When I came in,
and... thank you for thinking of me.
- He's the only family I have.
- I get it.
He's like my family too.
Oh, you're all family
at that station. [CHUCKLES]
- [CHUCKLES] We are.
- Yeah.
We are, but not Gibson.
I can't imagine my
kids not having him around.
I mean, Pru loves her some Uncle Jack,
and Joey tells him things that
he'd never tell me and Miranda.
They both spent time on the streets.
You know, when he
became part of my life,
after saving me from almost
burning my drunk self to death...
[CHUCKLES]
it was like stepping out of a dark room
into one with open windows and sunlight.
Did you see that? I think
he moved his fingers.
[SIGHS] Wishful thinking,
I guess. [CHUCKLES]
- [COMPUTER BEEPING]
- [SANJAY] Oh, my God.
The batteries have started off-gassing.
We have to get out of here.
Captain, the air is becoming unsafe.
I'm evacuating the
civilians to the balcony.
- [ANDY] Copy.
- Sullivan, what's the status
on the rescue cushion?
- [ROBERT ON RADIO] Thirty seconds.
- Kevin, back up.
Give me your sunglasses.
[GRUNTS]
[SANJAY GRUNTS, COUGHS]
All right.
Let's go. Let's go. [BREATHES HEAVILY]
- Kevin, go.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
- [VICTORIA] Sanjay.
- [COUGHS]
- [VICTORIA] Watch out. Watch out.
Give me a hand with
Phyllis. Sanjay, come here.
- [PHYLLIS] Ah! Mmm.
- [VICTORIA] I got you. I got you.
Okay.
Okay. Ah!
Hughes, the cushion is ready.
Send the first civilian.
[VICTORIA] All right.
Kevin, let's go.
[KEVIN GROANS]
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS, EXHALES]
[ANDY ON RADIO] He's down.
Get the next civilian ready.
[VICTORIA] Let's go.
[GRUNTS, SHOUTS]
[GROANS]
[ANDY ON RADIO] All clear.
Send the next one down.
- Okay, Phyllis.
- I can't.
- [COMPUTER CONTINUES BEEPING]
- [BUILDING CRASHING]
- Phyllis. Phyllis, yes, you can.
- [GROANS]
Yes, you can, okay? It's over
in a second and then you're safe.
- [ANDY ON RADIO] Hughes, we're ready.
- No. Even if I make it,
I'm going to jail.
- You don't know that.
- [SCOFFS]
You don't know that but if you stay,
this fire will kill you
if the smoke doesn't.
Hughes, do you copy?
"She died at the office."
- No one is dying.
- God, so depressing.
Stop. No one is dying today, okay?
This is not the end of your story.
You have so much to give
the world with your knowledge
and your experience,
but we need to go, okay?
Let me help you jump. Let me help you.
- Just sit on the edge of the balcony...
- I said no!
What part don't you get, lady?
Captain, civilian refuses to jump.
Can you... encourage her?
Yeah, I don't... It's not happening.
Wiggins, why isn't
that fire knocked down?
[WIGGINS ON RADIO] Standpipe got
damaged in the blast, Captain.
We gotta run a line down to the engine.
Copy. Keep me posted.
Those batteries are
gonna go up any second.
- Ticktock, ticktock, ticktock.
- Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Bishop, you and Cutler get to the roof.
You're going to rappel down to
the balcony with an extra harness.
Put the civilian in it and
rappel down to the ground.
Hughes, we're going to rappel
the civilian to the ground.
Bishop's on her way.
[VICTORIA ON RADIO]
All right. Copy that.
I hope it works.
It's gonna work. It's gonna work.
♪ Sand beneath my feet ♪
♪ Salt of the earth ♪
♪ Coming back to me ♪
♪ Start of rebirth ♪
♪ Carry me Carry me ♪
♪ Carry me to the water ♪
♪ Wash my body and
bathe me in the smoke ♪
♪ Carry me, carry me ♪
♪ Carry me to the altar ♪
♪ And finally bring that river home ♪
♪ Bring that river home ♪
[BEEPING]
[ANDY] Civilian on the ground
and clear of the building.
♪ Carry me to the water ♪
Knock that fire down, 19.
♪ Wash my body And
bathe me in the smoke ♪
♪ Carry me, carry me ♪
♪ Carry me to the altar ♪
♪ And finally bring that river home ♪
♪ Bring that river home ♪
[AMELIA] There's no
change in his neuro exam,
but there's all kinds
of scarring on his brain.
It's called encephalomalacia.
Small punctate areas of microhemorrhages
from previous traumatic brain injuries.
It's possible he's lost some
fine motor skills on his left side.
Oh, he-he'll recover
that, right? In time?
He might, with physical therapy.
But some football players and
hockey players who have brains
that look like Jack's
go on to develop CTE.
It's a neurologic disorder
caused by the death of
nerve cells in the brain.
He is alive. That is a win.
It's not my call, but realistically,
I don't see a world
in which any doctor
or-or the department will
clear him to fight fires again.
Not after they see his scans.
I'm sorry.
We will continue giving him the
best care that we possibly can.
- You're still here.
- I'll go if you want me to.
Emmett, I'm sorry...
that your dad didn't tell
you what you needed to hear.
In the moments that I spent with him...
I think he was sorry too.
Hey. [SIGHS]
- I'm sorry.
- [CRYING]
[TRAVIS] I'm so sorry.
♪ Bring the truth back to light ♪
♪ Spoken out magnified ♪
♪ Tell the things better left unsaid ♪
♪ Before they cloud the
love inside your head ♪
♪ Feel the blood in your chest ♪
♪ As soon as you make amends ♪
♪ Hear the quiet in the eye of storm ♪
♪ Hold your breath for the unknown ♪
♪ Till we reach the shore ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Till the borderline ♪
[PANTING]
[JACK] You really should
have seen this coming.
I tried. I told you to go see a doctor.
I just hope you do a better job
looking out for the rest of the team.
Jack. [BREATHES HEAVILY]
You think they're gonna trust you?
I mean, you couldn't even
keep me safe, your best friend.
Stop. Stop it, stop it.
This is not my fault.
And you're not gonna pin it on me,
or use it to make me doubt myself.
I worked my ass off
to get to where I am.
I've given my life to
19 and everybody in it.
I supported every single
one of these people
when they got promoted over me.
I'm sorry you won't be a
firefighter again. I really am.
But what happened to
you is not my fault.
And I'm sure as hell
not gonna give up everything
I've ever wanted because of it.
I deserve to be captain, and
I am going to be better at it...
than Bishop, and Beckett,
and Ruiz, and Sullivan.
Better than my dad.
I'm gonna be the best damn
captain this station has ever seen.
Now you get it.
[ANDY SNIFFLES]
[SIGHS, SNIFFS]
- [REPORTER 1] Here she comes.
- [REPORTER 2] Chief. Chief Ross.
[REPORTER 3] Can we get a statement?
[MAYOR OSMAN] Hello,
ladies and gentlemen.
To a city in mourning,
I am happy to report
that Chief Natasha Ross has been
released to continue her recovery at home.
[REPORTERS CLAMORING]
Are you still the fire chief, Ms. Ross?
[MAYOR OSMAN] Chief Ross
has done excellent work.
And the disclosure of a relationship
that was against the rules
doesn't change that.
It's the rule, not the
chief, that needs to be replaced.
So, I've asked Chief Ross to stay on
and, fortunately for
the city of Seattle,
- she has accepted.
- [REPORTER 3] Chief Ross,
what do you think about that statement?
[REPORTER 4] Chief Ross, when
will you be back in office?
[REPORTER 5] How long has this
relationship been going on?
I'm sorry.
I fooled around with Kate.
What?
At the ball, after we broke up.
Gibson saw us.
I didn't want you to hear it
from him or anybody else. I...
It was messed up, and I'm sorry.
'Kay.
That's it?
Yeah, what? You want me to get all crazy
like your other exes? We were broken up.
- I mean, I know but...
- But you know Dixon died that night?
And so did the waitress, and
now her baby is all alone.
And Jack has a traumatic brain
injury that he might not wake up from,
and today, Phyllis is going to jail
because I wasn't
able to talk her into
- coming out of a building.
- You did talk her out.
- All right.
- She was coming out
and it would've been over if
that tech bro didn't pop off.
- Well, that's not enough.
- You saved her life.
And you almost lost
yours in the process.
Crisis One is supposed to
be about stopping things
before they get to that
point and I didn't.
Now she and I have to live with that.
So compared with all that... that
stuff, you and Kate hooking up?
[SIGHS]
We're owed a celebration.
What about a steak?
- [SCOFFS] It's a qualified win at best.
- [SMACKS LIPS] Ah.
Osman thinks that I am a
good political bet for now,
and that could change.
Let's get married.
- Robert Sullivan.
- [CHUCKLING] What?
We're public. You're
keeping your job. Why not?
We've been waiting
a long time for this.
You ever notice that we only
do this in times of crisis?
Do what?
Talk about marriage.
Paint a picture of a future together.
We fell in love in a war zone, and
we are addicted to the adrenaline.
Marriage is not about adrenaline.
You know, when you were
trapped in that rubble,
a thought crossed my mind
that I might lose you forever.
And suddenly...
[SIGHS]
nothing else seemed important anymore.
That's not adrenaline.
That's clarity.
I love you, Sully.
But if you really want me to
take your proposal seriously,
- ask me on a Tuesday...
- [CHUCKLES]
when the weather's crappy
and my hair looks... looks busted
and I've got raging coffee breath
and we're both grumpy and
need a shower, you know...
Then... Then I might say yes.
- [ROBERT] Uh-huh.
- [CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
Tomorrow's Tuesday.
[CHUCKLES]
[GURGLES]
Hey. This is my wife, Maya.
I was just telling her
about you and the baby.
Yeah, I can't do it.
You-You-You can't do what?
I answered all their questions,
and I filled out the paperwork.
[SNIFFS] What was I thinking?
- I'm sure it seems scary.
- I'm a single guy.
He's a baby.
I'm really sorry, Nanette.
[STAMMERS] I'm really,
really sorry. I-I... I can't.
[MAYA SIGHS]
We can.
- Really?
- Let's be his moms.
Yeah.
Doesn't mean we
can't still get pregnant.
And we're perfect candidates
for emergency foster care.
I'm a paramedic. You're a doctor.
♪ When the calm turns to chaos ♪
- Are you sure?
- Mm-hmm.
[CHUCKLES, SNIFFLES]
[CARINA] Hi, little
Liam. I... [CHUCKLES]
I'm Carina, and this is Maya.
♪ When the garden turns... ♪
And we'd like to be your moms.
[CHUCKLES] Hi.
♪ To come home ♪
G-Gibson's done. He won't
be cleared to work again.
- Okay, did Amelia say that?
- It's bad.
Okay? He... He has
scarring on his brain.
He-He could have long-term damage.
He's moving. I think he's waking up.
Jack, can you hear us?
You're in the hospital,
Gibson. You... You're all right.
[ANDY] Hi.
- [CHUCKLES]
- Captain.
♪ 'Cause there is
mercy in the deep end ♪
When's my next shift?
[MARSHA] Sweetie, you
just woke up. [CHUCKLES]
- [JACK] I'm ready.
- [BEN] Just take a look at you.
♪ So it's time to come home ♪
- Synced and corrected by ChrisKe -
-- for www.addic7ed.com --